William Moses Jones papers, Inclusive: 1896-1973, Bulk:1896-1907
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
William Moses Jones papers
Inclusive: 1896-1973, Bulk:1896-1907
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
598
Jones, William Moses
2 document boxes
The William Moses Jones papers contain personal photographs, correspondence, financial materials, collected publications, and educational materials such as class records, exams, and academic reports from Jones’ time at Yale and Baylor University.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
William Moses Jones was born in Copeville, Texas, on 1876 August 26. He attended Baylor from 1891 to 1898 and Yale from 1899 to 1900. He studied law at both schools and worked as a lawyer in Dallas, Texas, for most of his life. William Moses Jones married Osee Tom Cook Jones in 1903, and the couple had six children together. William Moses Jones died on 1973 August 6 in Houston, Texas, at the age of 96.
Scope and Content
The William Moses Jones papers include letters, books, pamphlets, and materials relating to his studies at Yale University and Baylor University, plus personal and collected materials. Correspondence includes several letters Jones received from a friend, his brother Davie, and his sister Lizzie. Yale materials include several yearbooks and other published materials. Baylor materials include several photographs, graduation invitations, and other items. Notable is a photograph of Jones and other oratory society members at Baylor. Also included are various pamphlets and programs Jones collected throughout his life.
Arrangement
The William Moses Jones papers are in chronological order across the entire collection. This arrangement was probably done prior to being donated to The Texas Collection.
Currently, the William Moses Jones papers are arranged in three series: I. Correspondence, II. Education, III. General.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 598. Acquired 1973-10-09
Related Resources
Related references
William Moses Jones papers, Accession#598, Box #1, Folder#8, Yale Class Records 1926, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Find A Grave, Inc. "William Moses "Will" Jones Sr." Memorial #65992871. Databases. Accessed 2021 January 20.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Students -- Correspondence.
Subjects
Education -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Publications.; Yearbooks.
- Correspondence, 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence received by Jones while a student at Baylor University. The series is in good condition.
  - Baylor, Correspondence Received, 1897-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Education, 2
  This series contains educational materials and photographs from Jones' time as a student at Baylor and Yale. This series is in good condition.
  - Baylor, Education, 1895-1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baylor, Photographs, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baylor, Academic Reports [RESTRICTED], 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale, Class Book, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yale, Publication, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale, Class Record, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale, Class Record, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Collected Materials, 3
  This series contains various materials collected by Jones during his life and a copy of his obituary. This series is in average condition.
  - Publications (1 of 2), 1907-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publications (2 of 2), 1907-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes, 1907-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)